In this book i collected all
the prophecies of eibon ,
handed down from generation to
generation over more then 4,000 years .
You ungodly warlock .
Because of you this hotel and
this town will be cursed forever .
The seven dreaded gateways are
concealed in 7 cursed places .
Woe be unto him who ventures
near without knowledge .
Be careful what you do because
this hotel was built on one of
the 7 doors of evil
and only i could save you .
Woe be unto him who opens
one of the 7 gateways to hell ,
because through that gateway
evil will invade the world .
I told you martin , we can 't . All i
inherited was the hotel , nothing else .
But it 'd be such a pity not to .
Let me at least finish the plans .
No forget it . I won 't even charge you
for it . Look , really it 's not the case .
Ljust wanted to clean up the outside
walls a bit , and maybe tidy up inside
a bit and then , well , business
starts booming we 'll see .
It 's better we do it now because wait
four months or six and believe me ,
you are going to lay out .
You can 't imagine the effect
that double digit inflation is
having on housing .
Hi larry . How 's it going ?
Oh , good morning . I 'm gonna have
this whole wall finished by tonight .
Great . Bye .
Outside is ok . Good old 1800th louisiana ,
but the interior .
I mean , hotels just aren 't ...
the eyes !
The eyes !
Eyes !
Arthur . Where 's that doctor ?
He 's on his way .
This man needs to get to a hospital .
I 'll clean up the wounds first . Have
you got any water ?
I 'm sorry , but till the plumber comes
back i 'm afraid i can 't get you any .
Then we 'd better move him right now .
Give me a hand , will you ?
Take the legs ... gently ...
ok , up , right . Thank you doctor .
It 's ok .
How can i check up on him ?
Ask me at the hospital . John mckay .
We 're off to a great start . Let 's just
hope there isn 't any lasting damage .
I sure would like to know how a man
can fall off a scaffolding 6 feet wide .
Liza . Hey , look at this picture .
Weird .
I wasn 't aware that you had
already scored a client .
Client ? There isn 't a soul here !
I guess it must have been arthur .
Yeah .
Hey , is anybody home ?
Just a minute , i 'm coming !
Good morning . Are you
the plumber ? Joe , right ?
Yes ma 'm . What 's the trouble ?
No , thank you . I 'm afraid i can 't tell you .
Nothing comes out of the faucets ,
and yet somehow the basement is flooded .
You tell me .
The whole basement ?
And how !
Well , let 's take a look .
Ok ! Follow me , this way . Off we go .
I hope it isn 't too serious . Watch out ,
the stairs are really slippery .
I 'm an old sewer rat .
Well , here it is . How long do
you think it will take ?
It 'll take as long as it takes !
Martha ? I made this little pathway
to the far end just forjoe .
Thank you martha .
Well , i 'll go take that look .
Where is arthur ?
He is upstairs , tidying up ,
we 're doing our best to help
yeah , i know . Thank you .
Listen , i 'll be going into town later .
Would you please make
me out a list of all the things
we 'll need ? Ok , don 't worry .
Arthur ! What are you doing in my room ?
I was looking for keys .
Which keys ?
I told ma i was gonna clean up the
rooms but some of them are locked .
Well , ljust have to find those keys ,
arthur , won 't i ? Or else we 'll
simply call a locksmith .
In the meantime , could you go up on
the roof and check the chimney ?
I think it is clogged .
I heard a car drive up before .
Was it joe ? Yeah . Why ?
You are liza , aren 't you ? Yes .
My name is emily .
I 've been looking foryou .
Joe !
Arthur ?
I don 't understand , emily .
How do you ...
don 't worry . I know the way by heart .
And there 's always dickey here .
Come liza . I 'll show you the way .
Joe ?
Emily . Why did you say i must
give up the hotel ?
I can 't explain it to you .
Just take my word for it .
Go back to where you came from
and hurry .
What 's the matter ?
I don 't know . He is in amazingly
good condition for a corpse
who is supposed to have been dead for 6 years .
Well , the d.a. Said to open him up
and see what he had for breakfast .
How about we give it
a try with ... forget it .
You wanna wire this old guy into
your brain wave machine ?
Why not ? Okay . Okay .
But you 're on your own with this one .
I warn you though . When i get back ,
i 'm gonna give him an autopsy .
Harris here .
Miller want you up at 24 on the double .
I 'm on my way honey .
Wait here for me jill . I won 't be long .
Mommy ! Mommy !
So , what did you do in the big apple ?
Just about everything a girl could do
without losing her good english
breeding and reputation ,
modeling , dancing , secretary .
I almost became an unsuccessful
fashion designer .
When this letter arrived
announcing the inheritance .
Big surprise , uh ?
More or less . I mean , i knew i had
a rich uncle who was a bachelor
with a lot of real estate
imagined for one day to the next
but i neverthat i 'd be running a hotel .
Tell me , with all those accidents ,
you know , joe the plumber
and the house painter .
Do you think you 'll give up now ?
I couldn 't do that if i wanted to .
This is my last chance .
Either i run this hotel or i go on relief .
Well i tell you what ,
when you get the hotel fixed up ,
i 'll come and stay there
so you can book me a room now .
Sure , you 've got it . The best in
the house .
Of course . How long do you think
it 'll be before it 's ready ?
I don 't know , it 's driving on so much .
Arthur and martha are more of a
hindrance then a help .
They just can 't seem to get it together .
Well , if you hired them ,
you can fire them .
But , i can 't fire them .
They came with the hotel .
Strange , i 've never heard of them .
Dr. Mckay ,
dr . Mckay ,
you 're wanted on the phone .
It 's the hospital .
Thank you . Excuse me .
Oh ... harris , hi .
What ?
... in heaven
give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us ourtrespasses , as we forgive those
who trespass against us .
Lead us not to temptation , but deliver us from evil .
Amen .
... and as we commit the souls of
joe and mary ann , to ourfather
in heaven we pray together ,
oh merciful father ,
watch overjill , their daughter
whom joe and mary ann 's untimely departure
has left alone in this world , as a helpless child
confort her , and guide her , and give her strenght
we ask this , o lord ,
in the name of the father and of the son ,
and of the holy ghost . Amen .
Courage , my child
liza !
Liza !
Emily ?
Why didn 't you listen to me liza ?
We blind see things more clearly .
I wanted to spare you , but now
i 'll have to tell you everything .
60 years ago everybody in this
hotel disappeared .
Every last person .
A painter called schweik ,
who lived here closeted in his room
had found a key .
What key ? The seven gateways to hell .
This house was constructed
on one of the ...
who else is here ? There 's nobody here .
I can feel a presence .
Somebody else is in here .
No , emily . Nobody is here .
Yes , it 's him . He is here again .
He has come back to the hotel .
Get ahold of yourself ,
emily , please . What is this ?
That ? A painting , just an old painting .
There 's the bell .
That 's the bell from room 36 .
That 's where he was killed , in his room !
36 was schweik 's room ,
the man who found the key .
He has returned , liza .
Don 't ever enterthat room .
Now look emily , i 've lived in ny
all my life and if there is one thing
i 've learned not to believe in it 's ghosts .
I was lucky to inherit this hotel .
The first good break i 've had .
It 'll take more than a faulty electrical
contact or some crazy story to make me
give it up .
Emily ! Emily ! Emily !
Liza ! John !
Hey , hey , calm down , calm down .
Take it easy , take it easy , come on .
But i saw him . There , nailed to the wall .
He ...
see these nails .
Well , they certainly look old ,
but this seems more like rust
than blood .
Now it seems so impossible , so absurd .
And yet ... i don 't know .
Now look , come and tell me
exactly what you saw , hmm ?
No , never mind . It 's useless .
I guess i must have a pretty wild
imagination . Hmm ?
I got carried away with that story
that emily told me about room 36 .
Emily ? Who 's emily ? The blind girl
that lives in the old house
by the crossroads .
There 's no blind girl living there .
And i know everyone around here .
The book ! The what ?
The book that was on the desk . It 's gone !
Open two walls and enterthe basement
and then you 'll have a room
for a kitchen and maybe for a laundry .
Huh ?
What do you think of that ? Martin ,
i 've already told you .
I don 't have the money .
Do whateveryou want to as long
as it doesn 't cost . I have carte blanche ?
Carte blanche , but not a blank check .
Okay ? Okay . Well , the
first thing we do is bring someone
in to pump out all the water .
That i can get done real cheap .
And then ... oh , and on the other side
i 'll make a living room
and a game room . Have you got
the original plans of the cellar by any chance ?
There was another book here .
A different one .
You wanna buy the book
no , not this one .
The one that was here before ,
just a second ago . That book has
been there fortwo years .
Nobody wants to buy it . It 's very
nice though . Very , very interesting .
Liza ! What 's wrong ?
About the book ? I was just looking
for ... what ? Is anything the matter ?
You look sick .
You 're sure it 's nothing ?
I 'm just a little tired that 's all .
I think i 'm beginning to see things .
I get the picture . Later i 'll have to
go to the town hall and dig out
the originals from the files .
Re-open that hotel ? Uh , huh .
Anyway , all the turn of the century
building plans are on those upper
shelves there .
They should be under what
the cards say , m 13,012 .
Well , let 's get them down and look at them .
You surprised me mr . Avery .
You haven 't heard about ourtown
employees latest labor victory ?
It tooks three weeks strike to win .
Yeah . It was something about lunch .
An earlier break .
I 'm sure you 'll be ok on your own .
I 'll be out until one or a quarter of .
You feel completely at home now ,
you hear ? Have a happy lunch .
Thank you .
I 'm gonna lock the door ,
that way you won 't be disturbed .
First from one to two ,
and now from twelve to one .
Three weeks of picketing .
A great labor victory !
Now , then . M 13,012. manderville .
7 doors hotel . Hotel ... 7 doors .
What the ... ? !
" The 7 dreaded gateways to hell
are concealed in 7 cursed places . "
" And the day the gates of hell are opened ,
on that day the dead will walk the earth . "
Good boy , dicky , good boy .
Who 's there ? Who 's there ?
Answer me ! I know you 're there !
Where are you ? Who are you ? Who ?
I know it 's you . I can sense it .
What do you want from me now ?
What is it now ? Schweik , i know you 're here .
No , no , schweik !
Go away ! I don 't want to go back !
You can 't take me .
I don 't want to go back .
Stop tormenting me ! Don 't get
any closer ! Don 't get any closer !
No ! Go away ! Leave me in peace .
Don 't touch me !
You can 't take me back !
I did what i 've been asked ,
now leave me alone ! Go ! Go away !
No ! I never spoke . You can 't
condemn me ! I don 't want to go back !
Attack dicky ! Attack dicky ! Attack !
Dicky ! Dicky ! Don 't let them get
near me ! Attack ! Attack ! Chase them
away ! Attack ! Get rid of them , dicky !
Attack ! Dicky ! Attack !
Good boy .
Good boy . Good boy , dicky .
You made them go away .
Martha ? Arthur ? Arthur ?
No ! No ! No !
Stop it ! Liza ! Liza ! Stop it !
Liza , come on , it 's me .
Come on , calm down .
Come sit down ,
i saw arthur , come on sit down .
He was dead but ...
liza , liza , stop it !
I 'm sick of hearing all these stories .
What stories ? Well , like the first one .
There was a man nailed to the wall in room 36 .
And the blind girl that doesn 't exist .
Emily 's real . She does exist . I saw her .
I spoke to her .
The girl that lives in the old house
by the crossroads ? Yes !
That house has been abandoned
forthe last 50 years .
But that 's not true . It 's not possible .
I was there ! I mean i went there .
I was there .
Yes , i know you were there . I found
the book you left for me to read .
You found the book ? And i read it .
What did it say ? Show me where is arthur .
Here ? And he tried to kill you ? Huh ?
Please john , you must believe me .
I swear . So where is arthur now ?
But i don 't know ! He attacked me !
I was trying to break free .
He was here !
The cuts on my ... there are no !
I must be going crazy . Perhaps , or else ...
who are you liza ? Who are you really ?
John , i don 't understand you .
What a question . Why do you ask ?
Because according to the book of eibon ,
this hotel is one of the
7 gateways to hell .
" And you will face the sea of darkness
and all therein that may be explored . "
Strange . There isn 't a soul in sight .
Yea . Well , we 'll be at the hospital
pretty soon .
I wanna talk to harris .
Where is everybody ?
Let 's try the laboratory .
But john ... no , liza , i 'm a doctor ,
and i won 't accept irrational explanations
i want to talk to harris .
I 'm gonna call the fbi .
John !
The elevator ! Get the hell going !
Jill ?
Jill !
Harris ! What the hell is going on
around here ?
I don 't know . I think i 'm going crazy .
Here they come !
It 's jill .
She was in the autopsy theater all alone .
This way .
Come on .
No !
We 're underthe hotel . Impossible !
It 's impossible ! It 's crazy .
What 's happened ? Why are we here ?
Come on .
" And you will face the sea of darkness
and all therein that may be explored . "